# **Edith Chevallier Software Engineer**

edith.chevallier@hotmail.fr | +49 16 258 82 128 | 12049 - Berlin www.edithchevallier.com

## **ABOUT**

I am a software engineer passionate about JavaScript, with solid technical experience in Vue and its related frameworks and UI libraries. With a focus on end users, I utilise best practices to always produce clean and maintainable code, while constantly checking for new technologies to play around with. I am a team player who values straight-forward communication, exchanging knowledge, and always keeping a positive attitude in order to support teammates and achieve my company's goals.

## **EXPERIENCE**

01.2021 - Today (1 year and 2 months): Junior Front-end developer Artnight (Realtainment GmbH)

#### Core tasks:

- Building, maintaining and releasing features using Nuxt and VSF2 app based on stake-holders' requirements while keeping apps performant and mitigating codebase complexity with a strong collaboration with BE (Pimcore):
  - o Set up in-app notifications' system MVP using ravenhub.io (Nuxt)
  - o Set-up **e2e testing** and mitigate tests flakiness using cypress.io (Nuxt)
  - o Set up **personalised Gift-card feature** (VSF2)
- Building, maintaining and releasing internal UI library using SCSS/Post-CSS, storybook, and Buefy:
  - o Write easy to read and reusable UI components while keeping a high level of performances
- Reporting and fixing bugs
- Keeping technology up to date:
  - o Update Nuxt 2 app to Nuxt Bridge (Nuxt 3 when not Beta)
- Scrum methodology:
  - o Dailies, sprint planning, sprint refinement, retrospective
  - o Together with PM and Design, identify pitfalls and code limitations in early stage of features' creation
  - o Evaluate story points based on complexity

#### Side tasks:

- Presenting features to stakeholders and company
- Write documentation (publishing package, docker test env commands, conventional commits...) hosted on Digital Ocean and notions
- Managing project (interaction with stakeholders, wrote Epic and tickets for notification feature, establish design using Figma)

## **PROJECTS**

# Vue.js - VGG-garden (production)

Building a full-stack app for a community garden featuring: contact form, translation, progressive images, smooth scrolling.

n linked

github

**SKILLS** 

# Languages:

Javascript Node.js HTML CSS

## Frameworks:

Vue.js Nuxt VSF React.js Express.js

## Data base:

PostrgreSQL

#### Other:

Bootstrap
Buefy
vue-formulate
i18n plugin
Amazon Web
Services (S3, SES)
JSON
Eslint
Figma

Webpack GIT/Gitlab

## React.js - Portfolio

Final project of the bootcamp, building a web app featuring contact.

# React.js - Social-Network (production)

Realisation of a social-network website featuring: registration, login, pw reset, request, accept and end friendship, private and public chat.

# Vue.js - Imageboard (production)

Developing an image uploading platform using S3 and featuring comments/ image deletion. Vue.js

# Handlebars - Petition (production)

Setting up a petition app featuring login, signature canvas, list of signers per country or total, editing profile and signature.

#### PREVIOUS EXPERIENCES

03.2019 - 12.2019 : Account Manager - Mobile marketing - *youappi GmbH* Extended user acquisition knowledge on mobile with a focus on finTech products.

07.2016 - 09.2018: Account Manager - Desktop marketing - *ad2games GmbH* Acquired an essential understanding of websites' components from end users' experience to concrete monetization.

## **EDUCATION**

02.2020 - 04.2020: **Spiced Academy** Full Stack Web Development Immersive bootcamp focusing on Javascript.

09.2010 - 12.2015: ISTC - Communication and Marketing College (France - Lille)

- Master degree (International recognition honor)
- Oglethorpe University (USA Atlanta, GA) 1 year

# **VOLUNTEERING**

Coordinator - OpenTechSchool Berlin, Meet-Up

Support community by solving code-related issues together.

Coordinator - VGG, Community garden (Neukolln)

Support the community by organizing various events and gardening.

#### Volunteer - Purple Ride

FLINTA bike demo to empower women and to fight for more bicycle lines in Berlin.

Volunteer - Support Refugees

Participating in various tasks to welcome refugees.

LANGUAGES

English (fluent) French (native) German (trying a lot)